ＳＥＲＮ？ どういうこと？
あっ…！
タイムマシンは
ＳＥＲＮが回収する
牧瀬 紅莉栖 岡部 倫太郎 橋田 至
３名は 一緒に来てもらう
SERN will take the time machine.
ああ…
SERN? What do you mean?
ま まゆりは…？
Makise Kurisu.
椎名まゆりは…
Okabe Rintarou.
Hashida Itaru.
You three are coming with me.
必要ない
What about Mayuri?
やめろ…
Shiina Mayuri is...
やめてくれ…
ＦＢのために…
...not needed.
ＦＢ… ＦＢ！
Don't.
Don't do it.
For FB... FB... FB...
あっ… あっ…
まゆり… まゆり！
まゆり…
Mayuri?
Mayuri!
なんだよ これ！
Mayuri?
離れて
What the hell is this?!
岡部 離れて！
岡部も殺されちゃう！
Get away from her.
許さない… 俺が あいつを！
Okabe, get away from her!
She'll kill you, too!
あっ
うっ…！
ふっ！
ぐあっ！
You'll pay for this.
くっ！
ぐあっ ぐう！
I'll make her pay for this!
うっ！
ぐあっ！
ああ…
うっ
42… ブラウン管…
点灯済み
ああっ
くっ！
はっ！
42.
ぐっ… 早く！
CRT.
はあ はあ はあっ！
くっ！
It's on.
岡部！
俺が行く！
Hurry!
ああ でも… もし 失敗したら！
早くしろ！
くっ！
うっ…
岡部！ あっ…
Okabe!
I'll go!
跳べよ～！
But if it fails...
Do it now!
Okabe!
Leap!
Metaphysics Necrosis
まゆりの祖母が亡くなったのは
Mayuri was still in elementary school
まだ まゆりが小学生の頃だった
when her grandmother died.
まゆりは 毎日 墓参りを欠かさず
She went to the grave every day.
それは 祖母が亡くなって
半年たっても 続いていた
Even six months after her grandmother's death,
she was still going.
形見の懐中時計を手に
She always had her grandmother's
pocket watch in her hand,
いつもいつも 空を見上げていた
and she was always, always looking up at the sky.
まるで 祖母が迎えに来るのを
待っているように
Like she was waiting for
her grandmother to come and get her.
そんな ある日 光は差した
And then one day, there was a ray of light.
｢レンブラント光線｣
It was the kind called Rembrandt Lighting,
｢天使の梯子｣とも呼ばれる光
or an angel's ladder.
まゆりが
その光に引き込まれていくような
It felt like the light was drawing her up.
このまま
まゆりが消えてしまうような
Like she was going to disappear...
まゆり！
Mayuri!
オカリン…？
連れてなんていかせない
Okarin...
I won't let it take you.
まゆりは 俺の人質だ
You're my hostage.
人体実験の… いけにえなんだ
You're going to be my hostage.
I'll use you for human experiments.
口をついて出たのは
The words that came out of my mouth
ガキの頃 覚えた そんなセリフ
were from some show I'd seen as a little kid.
まゆりと２人で見たテレビで
Mayuri and I had watched it together.
マッドサイエンティストが
バカみたいに叫んでたセリフ
Some mad scientist, screaming like an idiot...
そっか…
あっ
I see.
まゆしぃは…
オカリンの人質なんだね
So Mayushii is your hostage, right?
じゃあ しょうがないね
Then, I guess I can't go, huh?
あ～！
おかしなオカリン
オカリン？
オカリン！
トゥットゥル－！
うん？
はあっ はあっ はあっ…
はあっ…
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
もしかして 居眠りでもしてた？
Were you napping?
あっ…
うん？
今は 何時だ？
えっ？
What time is it?
何時だ！
何よ…
What time is it?!
What?
もうすぐ ５時
買い物に行くんでしょう？
It's almost five.
You're going shopping, right?
買い物？
Shopping...
じゃあ 僕は ピザ注文しておくよ
お願い
I'll order pizza.
トロピカルスペシャルだけは
やめてね あれ 苦手なの
Thanks.
Just don't get the tropical special.
I hate that thing.
同意～
Agreed.
成功したのか？ タイムリープに
The time leap worked?
岡部
まゆりは？ まゆりはどこだ!?
Okabe?
Where's Mayuri? Where is she?!
何なのよ… やぶから棒に
What's wrong with you, all of a sudden?
まゆ氏なら るか氏のとこに
Mayushii said she was going to Miss Ruka's,
to invite her to the party, remember?
パーティー誘いに行くって
さっき 出て行ったじゃん
くっ！
あっ
買い物 行くの？
Are you going shopping?
開発評議会は 中止だ
The development conference is canceled.
中止？ どうして？
何か あったん？
Canceled?
Why?
Did something happen?
今日は… これで解散だ
２人とも すぐ家に帰れ
We're done here for today.
Both of you, go home now!
どういうこと？
いいから帰るんだ！
What's going on?
Just go home!
いいな？ 絶対だ！
Okay? Do it!
何なの？
携帯がかかってきたと思ったら…
What's with him?
His phone starts ringing, and then...
あっ…
携帯？
Phone?
トゥットゥル－！ まゆしぃです
今 電話に出られません
This is Mayushii.
I can't answer the phone right now!
ご用の方は…
くっ はあっ はあっ はあっ…
If you'd like to leave a message...
世界線が
大きく変わった様子はない
There's nothing to indicate
that the world line changed.
Ｄメールのときとは違って
It's different than the D-mail.
本当に
今日の午後５時に 戻ってきたんだ
I really am back at 5:00 PM.
ガタンガタ～ン 新幹線～
It's the bullet train!
違うでしょ？ 新幹線は白いの
No, the bullet train is white.
このあと まゆりが
鈴羽を連れて帰ってきて…
After this, Mayuri will return with Suzuha.
警察に駆け込むか？
いや 誰が信じる？
Should I go to the police?
No, who'd believe me?
未来から
タイムリープしてきたなんて…
That I've come from the future?
あと ３時間で
何とかするしかない！
Three hours left...
I have to do something!
まゆり！ まゆり！
Mayuri!
Mayuri?!
あっ おか… あっ いえ…
O-Oka... No, Kyouma—
凶真さ…
まゆりは どこだ!?
Where's Mayuri?!
えっ あ… もう 帰りましたけど…
Sh-She already left.
帰った？ いつだ！
Left?
When?
さ… 30分ぐらい前でしょうか
Th-Thirty minutes ago, I guess.
ラボに戻るって言ってましたけど
She said she was going back to the lab.
戻ってないんですか？
あっ…
Didn't she get back?
Um, I'm sorry.
あの すみません せっかく
パーティーに誘ってもらったのに
It was so nice of you to
invite me to the party, but...
僕 今日は どうしても…
どこかに寄るとは
言ってなかったか!?
Did she say she was stopping anywhere?
えっ まゆりちゃん… ですか？
いえ…
Mayuri-chan?
No...
もし 見かけたら すぐ俺に
電話するように言ってくれ！
If you see her, tell her to call me right away!
はっ はい…
O-Okay.
世界線が
変わっていないということは
If the world line hasn't changed,
まゆり自身の行動は
then if I don't do anything different,
俺が何かをしない限り
変わらないはずだ
she should do the same things as last time.
どこだ！
Where is she?
にゃんにゃん！
Nyan-nyan!
ﾌｪｲﾘｽは 今 電話に出られないにゃ
ご用の方は…
Feyris can't answer the phone right now.
If you need something...
くっ…
どこにいるんだ まゆり
Where are you, Mayuri?
あっ！ まゆりか？
Mayuri?
おあいにくさま
Too bad.
あっ 助手か…
Assistant...
今日は もう解散だと言っただろう
I told you, we're done today.
早く帰って…
端的に答えて
Go home—
Be honest.
You time leaped from the future, didn't you?
あんた 未来から
ﾀｲﾑﾘｰﾌﾟしてきたんじゃない？
なっ あ…
なぜ 分かった？
How could you tell?
携帯に出た瞬間
人が変わったみたいになったから
The second you answered the phone,
you seemed to change.
From the way you're acting,
その様子だと
何かあったってこと？
I can guess that something happened.
ああ
だが 詳しく話している時間はない
Yeah.
But I don't have time to give you the details.
とにかく 逃げるんだ
逃げるって どこに？
Just run.
Run? Where?
どこでもいい
Anywhere.
なるべく ラボから離れるんだ
分かったな
Just get away from the lab.
Got it?
後で ちゃんと聞かせてよ
Tell me later, okay?
ああ ダルにも伝えてくれ
分かった
Yeah. Tell Daru, too.
Got it.
岡部
何だ？
Okabe...
What is it?
変なことは しないでね
Don't do anything weird.
分かってる
I know.
岡部 倫太郎～！
あっ…
Okabe Rintarou!
Hey, where's Ochanomizu—
あのさ 御茶ノ水って…
まゆりを見てないか!?
Have you seen Mayuri?!
あ… 椎名まゆり？
Shiina Mayuri?
ああ ちょうど今
パーティーに誘われて…
She just invited me to your party—
どこだ!?
あっ そこを 右に曲がったとこ…
Where is she?
Turn right, up there...
ああっ
ねえ 御茶ノ水って どっち～？
Hey, which way is Ochanomizu?
綯が買い物 行くから
送ってかなきゃ なんだけど～
I have to take Nae shopping...
道なら 交番で聞け！ それと…
Ask at the police box!
And once you've taken her, don't come back!
送ったらお前も 戻ってくるな！
どういうこと～？
What do you mean?
理由は 後で話す！
ふう…
I'll tell you later.
まゆり…
Mayuri...
まゆり！
ああ オカリン
Mayuri!
Okarin!
見て 一番星！
Look! It's the first star!
あ… あっ 何？
What?
いいから… 一緒に来るんだ！
Just come with me!
ええ？ パーティーは？
中止だ
What about the party?
It's canceled. I told Kurisu and Daru.
もう 紅莉栖とダルにも言ってある
ええ… どうして？
Why?
後で説明する！
I'll tell you later!
でも… 鈴さん 誘っちゃったし
ダル君だって ピザ頼む…
But I asked Suzu-san to come, too,
and Daru-kun was ordering pizza...
いいから言うことを聞け！
Just listen to me!
オカリン…
Okarin...
ああ…
すまない
I'm sorry.
まゆしぃは よく分からないのです
Mayushii doesn't understand...
オカリンは いつも
よく分からないことするけど
You always do things I don't understand,
今日のオカリンは
ホントに分からないよ
but today, I really don't understand you.
実験…
やっぱり やりたかったのかな？
Did you really want to
do the experiment, after all?
まゆり…
Mayuri...
そういうわけじゃない
That's not it.
でも 今は
言うとおりにしてくれないか
But just for now, can you listen to me?
時間がないんだ
There's no time.
詳しいことは 後でちゃんと話す
I'll explain the details later, I promise.
うん…
Okay.
ごめんね まゆしぃ
なんか びっくりしちゃって…
Sorry. Mayushii just got scared.
Don't apologize.
謝るな まゆりは悪くない
It's not your fault.
すごい人だね
There are so many people here.
帰宅ラッシュの時間だからな
It's rush hour.
あれ～？
でも 誰もいないよ ホーム
Huh?
But no one's at the platform...
はっ…！
もう一度 お伝えします
Once again,
爆破の予告があったために
現在 運転を見合わせているのは…
the following lines have been shut down,
due to a bomb threat.
They said they don't know when
the trains will start again.
運転再開のめどは
まだ 出てないって
How stupid of me!
なんて うかつな…
こんなときに！
Not now...
オカリン？
まゆり 地下鉄だ 早く！
Okarin?
Mayuri, get to the subway now!
あっ…
岡部 倫太郎だな？
Okabe Rintarou, right?
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
あ…
一緒に来てもらう
You're coming with me.
そこ なに 止まってんだよ！
What are you standing there for?
どいてくれ！
あっ！
Move!
走れ！
えっ？ ああっ…
Run!
はあっ はあっ はあっ はあっ…
はあ はあ はあ はあ…
走れ！ 全力で走るんだ！
Run!
Run, as fast as you can!
はあっ はあっ はあっ…
あの人たちは？
Who are they?
うっ！
ああっ！
オカリン！
早く行け！
Okarin!
Go, quickly!
逃げろ まゆり！
Run, Mayuri!
えっ…？
ああ…
Shiina Mayuri was the one who died.
死んだのは 椎名まゆりです
岡部君…
いえ 岡部 倫太郎は 確保しました
Okabe-kun...
I mean, Okabe Rintarou has been captured.
Mayuri!
まゆり！
ぐっ！
Damn it!
くっそ～！
殺させない！
まゆり 絶対に助けてやる！
I won't let you kill her!
Mayuri, I will save you!
お前を…
I'll save you...
必ず！
...no matter what!
中止？ どうして？
Canceled?
Why?
何か あったん？
Did something happen?
ああ… 実はな
ミスターブラウンが
Yeah. Actually...
I got word
今晩 乗り込んでくるという情報を
キャッチした
that Mr. Braun is planning to return tonight.
オカリン また何かやらかしたん？
ああ ちょっとな
Okarin, did you do something again?
Yeah, I suppose so.
でも まゆりは？
まゆりには 俺が言う
But what about Mayuri?
I'll talk to her.
とにかく ここにいては危険だ
It's dangerous to be here.
本日は 解散とする
We're done here for today.
強引すぎたか…
Was I too forceful?
いや
怪しかろうと 何だろうといい
No...
It doesn't matter if I was acting weird.
とにかく今は みんなを
ラボから遠ざけるのが先だ
For now, I just need them away from the lab!
トゥットゥル－！ まゆしぃです
今 電話に出られません
This is Mayushii.
I can't answer the phone right now!
どうしても
時間がかかってしまう…
Why is it taking so long?
これじゃあ さっきと同じだ
It's going to end up like last time!
何とかして まゆりを… あっ
I need to find Mayuri.
Rukako
Hello?
もしもし
ルカ子 俺だ 岡部だ！
Rukako! It's me! Okabe!
Oka... I'm sorry, Kyouma—
あっ 岡… すみません 凶真さ…
まゆりは!?
Where's Mayuri?!
まゆりは そこにいるか!?
まゆりちゃんですか？
Is Mayuri there?
Mayuri-chan?
はい 今 帰るところ…
呼び止めるんだ！
Yes.
She's just heading bac—
Stop her!
俺が行くまで 絶対に
そこから動くなと伝えてくれ
Tell her not to move until I get there!
She said she was going back to the lab.
でも… ラボに戻るって
いいから言うとおりにするんだ！
Just do as I say!
はっ はい！ まゆりちゃ～ん
O-Okay.
Mayuri-chan!
うん？
ガタンガタ～ン 新幹線～
It's the bullet train!
違うでしょ？ 新幹線は白いの
No, the bullet train is white.
はあっ はあっ まゆり！
Mayuri!
ああ オカリン トゥットゥル－！
Okarin!
はあ はあ はあ…
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
これから ﾌﾌﾞｷちゃんのコス直して
ラボに帰るところだったのに
I was about to go fix Fubuki-chan's costume,
and then go to the lab.
Fubuki-chan?
フブキちゃん？ コスプレ仲間か
A cosplay friend of yours?
うん まゆしぃが作ったコスの糸が
ほつれちゃったんだって
Yeah!
She said a thread on the costume
I made came undone.
今 メールがあって…
そういうことだったのか
I just got a message from her.
So that's it.
直したら すぐ ラボに行くから
Once it's fixed, I'll go right to the lab,
so I'll make it to the party.
パーティーには 間に合うよ
待て パーティーは…
Wait. The party...
パーティーは 中止…
延期になった
The party was cancel...
I mean, it was postponed.
ええ～ どうして～？
Why?
どうしても
ラボが使えなくなってな
We can't use the lab.
しかたないんだ
It can't be helped.
そうなんだ…
それで
I see...
So I wanted you to come with me for a bit.
今からまゆりには ちょっと
つきあってもらいたい 今すぐだ
Right now.
フブキちゃんは？
すまんが 後にしてくれ
What about Fubuki-chan?
I'm sorry, but do it later.
大至急なんだ
あの… 何かあったんですか？
It's an emergency.
Um, did something happen?
ああ これから ちょっと遠出する
Yeah, we're going to be away for a while.
旅行だ
えっ ふ… ふっ 二人でですか？
On a trip.
Together?
Um, well...
いえ その…
う～ん
フブキちゃんは 明日でもいいけど
急だね
I can put Fubuki-chan off till tomorrow,
but this is very sudden.
どこに行くの？
それは 後で話す
Where are we going?
I'll tell you later.
電車の時間がないんだ
We don't have much time to catch the train.
でも… まゆしぃ
何の準備もしてないし
But Mayushii isn't ready at all, and...
お金も…
それは 心配しなくていい
Don't worry about it.
さあ 行くぞ
ああっ…
Come on, let's go.
待ってよ オカリン
Wait, Okarin!
Um...
あっ あの！
Huh?
え？
い… いってらっしゃい
G-Goodbye.
Yeah, bye-bye!
うん いってくるね～！
あっ…
秋葉原の駅 向こうじゃないかな？
Isn't Akihabara Station that way?
We're taking the subway.
地下鉄で行く
I see.
そうなんだ
ん…
It's been a really long time
なんか こうやって
オカリンに引っ張られて歩くの
すごい久しぶりだね
since you pulled me along like this.
ああ
Yeah.
あっ…
We're heading back.
戻るぞ
えっ？
Huh?
はあっ はあっ はあっ はあっ…
はあ はあ はあ はあ…
Okay.
よし 行くぞ
Let's go.
あっ
えっ？
From: Assistant
Subject: Did something happen?
Tell me later, okay?
紅莉栖か…
Kurisu, huh?
My watch isn't working...
あれ～？ まゆしぃのカイちゅ～
止まっちゃってる
えっ…
おかしいな…
That's strange.
さっき ネジ巻いたばっかりなのに
I just wound it.
There are so many people here.
随分 人が多いね
総武線が止まったんだろう
The Sobu line shut down.
えっ？ 止まってるの？
Shut down?
Yeah.
ああ
A bomb threat was called in.
爆弾を仕掛けたという電話が
入ったらしくてな
そうなんだ…
I see...
Hey, Okarin.
ねえ オカリン？
あっ
Um, well...
あのね まゆしぃは
聞きたいことが いっぱいあるけど
Mayushii has a lot of places she wants to go,
but it's okay for now.
今は 我慢しとくね
In exchange,
その代わり 終わったら
全部 聞かせてほしいのです
when this is over,
I want you to tell me everything.
Yeah.
ああ
約束する
I promise.
ごめんね
えっ？
I'm sorry...
オカリンの力になれなくて
ごめんね
I'm sorry I can't help you.
Let's have that party sometime.
パーティー いつか やろうな
うん いつか
Yeah...
Sometime.
Sometime...
いつか… 必ず
For sure.
まゆりおねえちゃ～ん！ あっ…
うん？
Mayuri-oneechan!
ええっ？
おっ おい
…じゃないの
It wasn't...
I didn't mean to...
わざとじゃないの…
あたし おねえちゃんを
I just wanted to surprise her...
びっくりさせようと思って…
I won't let you kill her!
殺させない…
まゆりは 俺が…
I will...
助ける！
...save Mayuri!
それから 俺は
まゆりを助けるために
何度もタイムリープをした
しかし